ADARSH H K E-Mail: adarshhk003@gmail.com

**Mobile:** +91-8496885315

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE:**

I want to enhance my career by giving in best of my efforts, Ideas along with company's interest and want to grow in professional as well as personal life and willingness to learn and effectively apply new technologies.

# **WORK PROFILE:**

Technical knowledge with 6+ years of work experience, skills gained from companies like IBM and BEL. I have worked on Production systems Support, Linux System Administration, Data warehouse support, MQ, Hardware and Network maintenance. I have gained expertise in SQL, ETL, Shell scripting, IBM WatsonX.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

- B.E(Computer Science Engineering) from Government Engineering College VTU Mandya in 2016
- 12th from Jawahar Navodaya Vidhyalaya CBSE, Udupi in 2012.
- 10th from Jawahar Navodaya Vidhyalaya CBSE, Chikkamagalore in 2010.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

**Programming Languages :** Shell script, SQL, Basic C, Ansible **Operating Systems :** RHEL Linux, UNIX AIX, Windows

Tools: Squirrel SQL, JIRA, Bugzilla, Genio ETL tool, IBM WatsonX, Kubernetes, MQ, GitHub

CERTIFICATION: Digital Certification on "IBM Cloud Private Infrastructure and Architecture" and "Think Like a Hacker"

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

### 1) # IBM India Private Limited, Bangalore

As Technical Support Professional

As Contractor from #Infinite Computer Solutions (India) Ltd.

June 2021 to July 2024 March 2019 to May 2021

Worked for IBM since March 2019 till date as **Technical Support Professional** for projects like IBM System Development Warehouse (**ISDW**) and Tool Control Infrastructure (**TCI**), B2B, **CAYCE** (Characterization and Yield Collaborative Environment) applications and participated in IBM **WatsonX** challenge and gained some AI knowledge.

ISDW is warehouse for Semiconductors chip manufacturing data for which the data comes from data-delivery software called TCI. Here my **Roles and Responsibilities**:

- Configuring various Data feeds and sending data to warehouse.
- Daily monitoring of ISDW and TCI application in both Production and Non-Production environment with Web based tools like Zabbix.
- Resolving the daily issues like Data Warehouse schema processing, diskspace problems and other monitor issue.
- Modification of Config file for cronjobs changes for AIX Servers and application Management.
- Provided support to customer for their technical queries via E-Mail, Bugzilla, Jira Tickets amongst other ways.
- Responsible for communicating Outages to customers during Fix Pack upgrades, site power Outages and Daylight-saving changes along with any unknown outage that happens.
- Responsible for WebSphere application Server (WAS) administration including deployment & recycles the applications.
- Used to document all the tickets and Preparing weekly Metrics reports.
- Archiving and retrieving the files from TSM servers (Tivoli Storage Manager).
- Also, part of Samsung Triage team which Provides 24/7 customer support for SEV1 issues.
- Regularly update and deploy monitoring scripts & TCI configuration files for the data feeds.
- Log analysis for finding detailed root cause of the issue/error and to get the solution to it.
- Involved Deployment of Immediate fixes necessary on the production servers to maintain the data flow constantly.
- Responsible for Installing New Versions of TCI on production, test & development servers each quarter.
- Troubleshooting the critical issues very effectively and solved it within time frame and helped in increasing the productivity of the project.
- Usage of MS Office products (e.g, Outlook, Excel) as well as Slack, GitHub and JIRA for planning and documentation of work
- Experience in the usage of PagerDuty, monitoring/on-call support.

2) # BEL - Bharat Electronics Ltd, Bangalore

As Contract Engineer at BEL Software center

As Vendor from Cauvery Info-tech

As Graduate Trainee Engineer

2019 2018

Feb 2017 to Feb 2018

In 2017, Started my career at **BEL** as a **Graduate apprentice Trainee Engineer** in Electronics Warfare & Avionics Strategic Business Unit and continued as **SystemAdmin & Network Engineer** through Vendor Company and later joined as **Contract Engineer** at Bharat Electronics software center.

During this time, I have gathered knowledge about system administration, Linux, Network operation & maintenance of switches routers and fibers. Here my Roles and Responsibilities:

- Maintenance of INTERNET and INTRANET Networks
  - > Installation of Network switches and monitoring them with ZABBIX and Nagios
  - > Providing data security by Network Access Controller i.e Navis Agent,
- Support for Linux and Windows
  - > Installation of Operating Systems, Printer and software and packages.
  - ➤ Remotely access computers using VNC & RDP and resolving issues
  - Antivirus support i.e with Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Also Provided Email support like creating Email ID, POP3/IMAP configuration and allocating storage in Space in SAN
  and Blocking spam Email to maintain Security.
- Involved in INFORMATION SYSTEM SECURITY audits.
- Designed, developed and maintained a web-based application written in ASP.Net, HTML

#### **PROJECTS:**

# #1 ISDW- IBM System Development Warehouse.

ISDW is a warehouse for manufacturing data. It is central database repository used for the storage of Testdata throughout the IBM Microelectronics manufacturing process. Datawarehouse comprises 18 distributed servers with databases at Burlington, Vermont, East Fishkill, NY, and Ireland. ISDW is 24x7 supports which involve many applications running on AIX servers, Both ETL Processes and java Applications will be running continuously to move the data from source to target Databases.

As a L2 support engineer I was responsible for providing complete support to all server and apps and make sure that data get processed through all application with no issues.

#### #2 TCI - Tool Control Infrastructure

TCI is a data-delivery software system. TCI receives the data files from TESTERS, converts the files to TEDS format and feeds the data to ISDW. TCI application located in Burlington, Vermont and currently deployed in Fishkill, NY, Bromont, Canada, Ireland, Singapore, and Taiwan. main function of TCI is to deliver data to specified locations in an automated fashion without any user or manual interaction.

# **PERSONAL DETAILS:**

Current Location: Bangalore. Karnataka Nationality: Indian

Marital status: Single Languages: Kannada, English, Hindi

The above information provided by me is correct to the best of my knowledge and I will work to the best of my abilities to level up to your expectations.

Place: Bangalore (ADARSH H.K)